Guide to the Brooklyn Ephemera Collection BCMS.0007
Brooklyn Collection
Brooklyn Ephemera Collection
circa 1840 – Present
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0007
22 Linear Feet in 26 boxes
The Brooklyn Ephemera Collection consists of catalogs, postcards, business cards, fliers, circulars, and other remnants of daily life in Brooklyn. Major portions of the collection relate to Brooklyn Public Library, local businesses, churches, and schools.
Provenance
This is an artifical composite collection made up of materials from many different sources acquired over several years.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject. Ephemera from similar sources are grouped under one subject heading (i.e. "Banks" and "Restaurants"), with sub-categories for each establishment, person, or organization.
Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Accruals
Accruals have been and will continue to be frequently added.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains historic and contemporary printed ephemera of Brooklyn. Although often created for temporary, practical business and social needs (i.e., a ticket stub for a dance or a business card), printed ephemera can often reveal much more nuanced information about the time and place in which it was produced. Commercial businesses, schools, municipal boards and commissions, and other clubs and organizations produced the material that is in this collection, which spans more than 150 years of Brooklyn history.
- Abbey, The (Box 1)
- African American History (Box 1)
- African American History to 1863 (Box 1)
- Albee Square (Box 1)
- Artists: Brooklyn Artists Gym (Box 1)
- Artists: General (Box 1)
- Artists: Michael Scott Berman Photography (Box 1)
- Artists: Tan, Tattfoo (Box 16)
- Artists: Tony Valez: This Is Brooklyn: Its Historic Districts and Landmarks (Box 1)
- Artists: Women Artists Living in Brooklyn (Box 1)
- Arts: Literary: General (Box 1)
- Arts: Literary: Brooklyn Book Festival (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Amateur Chamber Music Players, NYC (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: American Ballet Company (Box 16)
- Arts: Performing: Arts at St. Ann's (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Black Theater Alliance (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Brooklyn Conservatory of Music (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Brooklyn Lyric Opera Association (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Brooklyn Opera Company (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Brooklyn Philharmonic (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Brooklyn Philharmonia (Box 16)
- Arts: Performing: Brooklyn String Orchestra (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Catholic Diocesan Choristers (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Chelsea Theatre (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Concert Programs (Box 1, Box OS 9, Box OS 8)
- Arts: Performing: Dance (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Egbe Omo Nago Folkloric Ensemble (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: General (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Gilbert Dramatic Association (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Merce Cunningham & Dance Company (Box 16)
- Arts: Performing: Millennium Concert Hall Super Chanukah concert (Box OS 3)
- Arts: Performing: Pearl Primus Dance Company (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Philharmonic Society of Brooklyn (Box 1)
- Arts: Performing: Polish Theater Group (Box 1)
- Arts: Visual: Exhibitions (Box 1)
- Arts: Visual: Galleries: Summa Gallery (Box 1)
- Arts: Visual: Galleries: Object Image Gallery (Box 1)
- Arts: Visual: Galleries: Kentler International Drawing Space (Box 1)
- Arts: Visual: All Communities Arts (Box 16)
- Atlantic Yards (Box 1)
- Banks: Bank of the Manhattan Co. (Box 1)
- Banks: Bay Bridge Savings and Loan Association (Box 1)
- Banks: Bond and Mortgage Guarantee Company (Box 1)
- Banks: Broadway Trust Co. (Box 1)
  Related Materials
  Banks: Flatbush Trust Company
- Banks: Brooklyn Savings Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: Dime Savings Bank of Brooklyn (Box 1)
- Banks: Dime Savings Bank of Williamsburgh "70 Years", 1934 (Box 1)
- Banks: East Brooklyn Savings and Loan Association (Box 1)
- Banks: Flatbush Savings Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: Flatbush Trust Company (Box 1)
  Banks: Broadway Trust Co.
- Banks: Franklin Trust (Box 1)
- Banks: General (Box 1)
- Banks: German Savings Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: Greater New York Savings Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: Greenpoint Savings Bank (Box 1, Box OS 6)
- Banks: Hamburg Savings (Box 1)
- Banks: Kings County Savings Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: Lincoln Savings Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: Long Island Bank (Box 1)
  General
  John Lefferts Bank Note
- Banks: Municipal Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: National City Bank of New York (Box 1)
- Banks: North Side Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: People's Trust Company (Box 1)
- Banks: Roosevelt Savings Bank of the City of New York (Box 1)
- Banks: Savings Bank Trust Company 1946 Annual Report (Box 1)
- Banks: South Brooklyn Savings Bank (Box 1)
- Banks: Williamsburg Savings Bank (Box 1, Box OS 6)
- Banks: Williamsburg Trust Company (Box 1)
- Bathhouses (Box 1)
- Bay Ridge: Bay Ridge History by Ann Cagan (Box 1)
- Bay Ridge: Brevoort Directory of Bay Ridge Organizations, 1964; Brevoort Savings Bank of Brooklyn (Box 1)
- Bay Ridge: Community In Which You Live, 1950; Brevoort Savings Bank of Brooklyn (Box 1)
- Bay Ridge: Ovington Village Association (Box 1)
- Bay Ridge: Zoning Report, Dept. of City Planning, 1978 (Box 1)
- Bedford-Stuyvesant: General (Box 1)
- Bedford-Stuyvesant: Post-War Improvements, 1943 (Box 1)
- Belt Parkway: Sheepshead Bay Section of the Belt Parkway (Box 1)
- Biographical: Adams, Joey (Box 1)
- Biographical: Alexander, William (Earl of Stirling) (Box 1)
- Biographical: Ankers, John Henry (Box 1)
- Biographical: Avery, William (Box 1)
- Biographical: Beck, Julian (Songs of the Revolution) (Box 1)
- Biographical: Beecher, Henry Ward (Funeral Tickets and program) (Box 1)
- Biographical: Bergen, Teunis (Box 1)
- Biographical: Betts, Dorothy (Box 1)
- Biographical: Bonanno, Dominick (Box 1)
- Biographical: Boody, David A. (Box 1)
- Biographical: Buchanan, Jean Sinclair (Box 1)
- Biographical: Byrd, Richard (Box 1)
- Biographical: Cacchione, Peter V. (Box 1)
- Biographical: Cadman, S. Parkes (Box 1)
- Biographical: Carnegie, Andrew (Box 1)
- Biographical: Cashmore, John (Box 1)
- Biographical: Conway, Thomas W. (Box 16)
- Biographical: DeHart, Simon (Box 1)
- Biographical: Eaton, Dr. Darwin G. (Box 1)
- Biographical: Gerritsen, Samuel I. (Box 1)
- Biographical: Gordon, Jack (Box 1)
- Biographical: Hodnett, John Pope (Box 2)
- Biographical: Kevess family (Box 2)
- Biographical: Livingston, Robert R. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Loines, Stephen (Box 2)
- Biographical: Maas, Willard (Box 2)
- Biographical: Mack, Jean (Box 2)
- Biographical: Maddox, Samuel (Box 2)
- Biographical: Mahana, Mozelle (Box 2)
- Biographical: Moore, Marianne (Box 2)
- Biographical: Neilson, Kenneth (Box 2)
- Biographical: Niss, Lou (Box 2)
- Biographical: O'Dwyer, William (Box 2)
- Biographical: Ogden, Robert Curtis (Box 16)
- Biographical: Oppizzi, Angela Boglioli (Box 2)
- Biographical: Polley, Grahams (Box 2)
- Biographical: Proctor, Margery Wells (Box 2)
- Biographical: Robertson, D.W. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Ryan, James J. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Schroder, Charles (Box 16)
- Biographical: Schurtz, Carl (Box 2)
- Biographical: Seymour, Horatio (Box 2)
- Biographical: Shepherd-Moore, Marie (Box 2)
- Biographical: Solarz, Stephen (Box 2)
- Biographical: St. John, Francis R. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Storrs, Richard Salter (Box 2)
- Biographical: Tilton, Theodore (Box 2)
- Biographical: Tredwell, Daniel (Box 2)
- Biographical: Trommer, Marie (Box 2)
- Biographical: Tuckman, William (Box 2)
- Biographical: Tuttle, Horace (Box 2)
- Biographical: Vaux, Calvert (Box 2)
- Biographical: Vogel, Herb and Dorothy (Box 2)
- Biographical: Weber, David (Box 2)
- Biographical: Weinstein, Gregory (Box 2)
- Biographical: Weston, Charles B. (Box 2)
- Biographical: White, Alfred T. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Whitman, Walt (Box 2)
- Biographical: Wibecan, George E. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Willis, Louis C. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Wright, Samuel D. (Box 2)
- Biographical: Zabriskie Family (Box 2)
- Board of Education (Box 2)
- Board of Elections Acts and Instructions for Registers and Instructors (Box 2)
- Board of Health (Box 2)
- Board of Transportation (Box 2)
- Borough Hall (Box 2)
- Boy Scouts (Box 2)
- Breweries: Brooklyn Brewery (Box 2, Box 16, Box OS 4)
- Breweries: John F. Trommer, Inc. (Box 2)
- Breweries: Liebmann Brewery, Inc. (Rheingold) (Box 2, Box OS 3)
- Breweries: Long Island Bottling Company (Box 2)
- Breweries: Olde Keg Brewing Co., Inc. (Box 2)
- Breweries: Otto Huber Brewery (Box 2)
- Breweries: Piel Brothers (Box 2)
- Breweries: Schaefer Brewing Co. (Box 2, Box OS 4)
- Breweries: Welz & Zerweck's High Ground Brewery (Box 2)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Battery Bridge (Box 2)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge (Box 2, Box OS 6)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge: Centennial (Box OS 3, Box OS 4, Box OS 5, Box OS 7)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge: Centennial: Books & Pamphlets (Box 2)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge: Centennial: Cards, Invitations, Tickets etc. (Box 2)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge: Centennial: Commemorative Postage Stamp (Box 2)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge: Centennial: Flyers & News Releases (Box 2)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge: Construction & Opening (Box 2)
- Bridges: Brooklyn Bridge: Images (Box 2, Box OS 3)
- Bridges: Manhattan Bridge (Box 2)
- Bridges: Meeker Avenue Bridge (Box 2)
- Bridges: Thirteenth Avenue Bridge (Box 2)
- Bridges: Verrazano Bridge (Verrazzano-Narrows Bridge) (Box 2)
- Bridges: Williamsburg Bridge (Box 2)
- Brighton Beach: Brighton Beach Music Hall (Box 2)
- Brighton Beach: General (Box 2)
- Bronx: St. Mary's Recreation Center (Box 2)
- Brooklyn Academy of Design (Box 2)
- Brooklyn Academy of Music [2 folders] (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Bicentennial Commission (Box OS 6)
- Brooklyn Borough President: Annual Reports: Brooklyn Progress [5 folders] (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Borough President: Office (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Botanic Garden: Mailings (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Botanic Garden: Pamphlets and Flyers (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Botanic Garden: Reports and Newsletters (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Botanic Garden: Japanese House (Box 16)
- Brooklyn Communication Arts Professionals (BCAP) (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle (Box 3, Box OS 6, Box OS 7)
- Brooklyn Description and Travel (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Heights (Box 16)
- Brooklyn Heights Association (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Heights: Apprentices' Library (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Heights: General (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Historical Society: General (Box 3)
- Brooklyn Historical Society: Newsletters [3 folders] (Box 3)
- Brooklyn History Fair [2 folders] (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Information and Culture (BRIC): Celebrate Brooklyn! (Box 4, Box OS 6)
- Brooklyn Library: General (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Mercantile Library (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Navy Yard (Box 4, Box 16)
- Brooklyn Now (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Parents Music & Culture Committee (Box 16)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Book cards (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Booklists (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Book plates & pockets (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Arlington (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Astral (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Bedford (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Borough Park (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Brooklyn Heights/Business Library (Box 4, Box OS 3)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Brownsville (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Brownsville Children's [now Stone Avenue] (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Bushwick (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Business Library (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Carroll Park [now Carroll Gardens] (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Dekalb (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Eastern Parkway (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Flatbush (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Fort Hamilton (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Greenpoint (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Kings Highway (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Macon (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Mapleton (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Montague (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: New Utrecht (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Pacific (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Park Slope (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Prospect (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Red Hook (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Ridgewood (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Saratoga (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Sheepshead Bay (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: South Branch (Sunset Park) (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Tompkins Park (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Walt Whitman (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Branches: Williamsburg (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Brooklyn Collection (Box 4, Box OS 3)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Brooklyn Public Library Bulletin (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Call Slips, Stickers, Labels (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Career Opportunities (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Cataloguing & Book Ops (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: Centennial Gala Program (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: Collection Guides (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: Equipment & Receipts (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: General [2 folders] (Box 4, Box 16)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: Ingersoll Library (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: Ingersoll Library Scrapbook: "Publicizing a New Building" (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: Writers Circle (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Central Library: Youth Wing (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Exhibits and Programs (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Forms (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: "F.Y.I" Staff Newsletter (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Gala Programs (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: History (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Library Cards (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Library Guides and Directories (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Marketing Campaigns (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Miscellaneous Labels, Book Plates, Manual, Call Slips, Book Card (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Mouse Pads (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Public Library: Summer Reading (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Public Library: World Telegram and Sun Cartoon (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Public Library Foundation (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Queens Expressway (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Rapid Transit Co. (Box 5)
- Brownsville: "A Post-War Plan for Brownsville" (Box 5)
- Brownsville: Brownsville Boys Club For the Betterment of Youth (Box 5)
- Brownsville: Brownsville Community Council (Box 5)
- Brownsville: Brownsville Tomorrow Maps (Box 5)
- Bush Terminal: General (Box 5)
- Bushwick: Houses: Duryea House (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: ACME Sales Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: ACME Smoked Salmon (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Adams Express Company (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Advertising: Consumer Goods (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Advertising: Cookbooks (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Advertising: Grocers, Markets, and Bakeries (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Advertising: Labels (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Advertising: Manufacturing (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Advertising: Matchbooks (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Advertising: Services (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Ajax Chemical Fire Engine (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Ansonia Clock Company (Box OS 3)
- Business & Industry: Arkenau Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Austin, Nichols & Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Automobile Supply Manufacturing Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Baker & Fox (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Baker, H.J. & Bro. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Balch Price Co. (Furs) (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: H. Batterman Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: E.W. Bliss Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Bohannan, Wilson (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Broadway Tea House (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Brooklyn Brew Shop (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Brooklyn Furniture Company (Box OS 3)
- Business & Industry: Brooklyn Lace Paper Works (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Brooklyn Lock Company (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Brooklyn Real Estate Exchange (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Brooklyn, New York: Economic Resource Profile (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Bushwick and Newtown (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Central Supply Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: The Chat (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Chrome Steel Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Cohn's Credit Clothing Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Colonial Works Inc. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Community Bookstore (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Consumers Malted Milk Company (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Convisers' Uneeda Credit Clothing Co. (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Day's Style Shop (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: DeMilt, Wilburt (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Doxsee's Little Neck Clam Products (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Dunlap & Co. (hats) (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Ebinger (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Empire Stores (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Force, Wm A. & Co (Box 5)
- Business & Industry: Gardiner-Lucas Licorice Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Gleason-Tiebout Glass Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Graham Chemical Pottery Works (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Gumpert, S. & Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Hall-Mark Electrical Sales Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Hammett, J.L. Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Hammond, C.S. & Co. (Box 6, Box 16)
- Business & Industry: Herwig, P.C. and Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Holliston Mills, Inc. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Houchin's Machine Works (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Ideal Novelty and Toy Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Ingersoll Paint/Patron's Paint Works Inc. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Jessal Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Kason Hardware Corporation (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Kissel, John & Son (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Kresner Butter & Egg Co. / Kresner's Poultry Farms (Box OS 3)
- Business & Industry: La Rosa and Sons, Inc. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Long Island Express Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Masury, John W. & Sons (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Mergenthaler Linotype Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Metropolitan Greenhouses (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Miller, William P. Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Modern Biscuit Corporation (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Munke Jack Corporation (Box 16)
- Business & Industry: Murray, W.H. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: New York Saw Works, Inc. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: New York Stamping Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Nurnberg Thermometer Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Oppenheim, Collins & Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Orange Outdoor Advertising (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: P. Freel (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Pioneer Instrument Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Potdevin Machine Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Read, Gleason and Read (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Reid's Union Dairy, Inc. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Renken, M.H. Dairy Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Rikers Laboratories (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Robbins, D. & Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Roberts Numbering Machine Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Roehrig-Bielenberg Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Rosenberg & Son: Men's, Boys' and Children's Clothing (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Rotary File Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Sacol Laboratory (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Schaefer & Budenberg (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Schiercke, Henry C. (Box 16)
- Business & Industry: Sleepwell Metal Bed Co (Box 16)
- Business & Industry: Smith, Willard H. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: South Brooklyn Steam Engine and Boiler Works (Box 16)
- Business & Industry: Sperry Gyroscope Co., Inc. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Stern's Pastry Shop (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Sternau, S. & Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Stimpson, Edwin B. Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Sturtevant Overin Co., Inc. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Tagliabue, C. J. Mfg. Co. [5 folders] (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Tension Envelope Co. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Treat Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Trunz Meat Stores (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Union Porcelain Works (Greenpoint) (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Urban Oyster (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Vitagraph Company of America (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Vogel, William, & Bros. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Walker, A.H. (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Ward Baking Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Warshavsky & Cohen (Box 16)
- Business & Industry: Waterbury Cordage (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Wechsler and Abraham (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Williams, George A. and Son (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Woodhouse, J.S. Company (Box 6)
- Business & Industry: Zeman Brothers (Box 6)
- Calendars (Box OS 10)
- Canarsie (Box 6)
- Carnivals (Box 6)
- Carroll Gardens (Box 6)
- Celebrations: Anniversary Day (Box 6)
- Celebrations: Brooklyn and Long Island Fair, 1864 (Box 6)
- Celebrations: Brooklyn Anniversaries (Box 6)
- Celebrations: Centennial of Inauguration of George Washington, 1889 (Box 6)
- Celebrations: Gay Pride (Box 6, Box OS 6)
- Celebrations: Hudson-Fulton Celebration (Box 6, Box 16)
- Celebrations: West Indian Day Parade/Carnival (Box 6)
- Cemeteries: The Evergreens Cemetery (Box 6)
- Cemeteries: Jewish Cemeteries (Box 6)
- Chamber of Commerce (Box 6, Box 16)
- Chicago Public Library (Box 6)
- Children (Box 6)
- Churches: Ainslie Street (Presbyterian) (Box 6)
- Churches: All Saints Afro-American Catholic Church & Community Center (Box 6)
- Churches: All Saints (Episcopal) (Box 6)
- Churches: All Souls Universalist (Box 6)
- Churches: Arlington Ave. (Presbyterian) (Box 6)
- Churches: Armenian Church of the Holy Martyrs (Box 6)
- Churches: Baptist Temple (Box 6)
- Churches: Beecher Memorial Church (Box 6)
- Churches: Bensonhurst Presbyterian (Box 6)
- Churches: Bethany Baptist (Box 6)
- Churches: Bethany Chapel (Reformed Episcopal) (Box 6)
- Churches: Bethany Presbyterian Church (Box 6)
- Churches: Bethel Seventh Day Adventist (Box 6)
- Churches: Bethlehem Evangelical (Box 6)
- Churches: Bethlehem United Church of Christ (Box 6)
- Churches: Brooklyn City Mission (and Tract Society) (Box 6)
- Churches: Brooklyn Tabernacle (Box 6)
- Churches: Bushwick Avenue Congregational Church (Box 6)
- Churches: Bushwick Central M.E. Church (Box 6)
- Churches: Bushwick Dutch Reform Church (Box 6)
- Churches: Bushwick Reformed Dutch Church (Old) (Box 6)
- Churches: Canarsie Reformed Church (Box 6)
- Churches: Cathedral Basilica of St. James (Box 6)
- Churches: Central Congregational (Box 6)
- Churches: Central Methodist Episcopal (Box 6)
- Churches: Central Presbyterian (Box 6)
- Churches: Church of Good Tidings (Universalist) (Box 6)
- Churches: Church of Holy Trinity (Episcopal) (Box 6)
- Churches: Church of the Assumption of the Blessed Virgin Mary (Box 6)
- Churches: Church of the Messiah and Incarnation (Box 7)
- Churches: Church of the Pilgrim (Congregationalist) (Box 7)
- Churches: Church of the Transfiguration (Box 7)
- Churches: Congregational Association of New York and Brooklyn (Box 7, Box OS 3)
- Churches: Emmanuel Baptist (Box 7)
- Churches: Epiphany (Lutheran) (Box 7)
- Churches: First Presbyterian (Box 7)
- Churches: First Presbyterian City Park Branch (Box 7)
- Churches: Flatbush (Reformed) (Box 7)
- Churches: Flatbush Christian (Disciples of Christ) (Box 7)
- Churches: Flatbush Congregational (Box 7)
- Churches: Flatlands Dutch Reformed (Box 7)
- Churches: Fleet Street (Methodist Episcopal) (Box 7)
- Churches: Fourth Church of Christ, Scientist (Christian Scientist) (Box 7)
- Churches: German Evangelical (Lutheran) (Box 7)
- Churches: Goodsell Memorial (Methodist Episcopal) (Box 7)